Romeu Fialho

Email: romeubaptistafialho.dev@gmail.com, Phone: 967092983, Portfolio: romeufialho.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a Gameplay Programmer experienced with C#, C++ and cooperating with designers and artists to create gameplay features and mechanics in Unity or Unreal Engine. Previously studied base programming languages like C as well as Operative Systems, Computer Hardware, and Web Development.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Skills in C#, C++, OOP languages.
- Experience working with Unity and Unreal Engine.
- Over 2 years of experience working with and around video games.
- Worked with 3 small teams to create indie experiences.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

GAME PROGRAMMER. FREELANCE

March 2020 – Present Day

- Developing indie games and experiences using Unity and Unreal Engine.
- Keen to working as a team.

GAME PROGRAMMER, MONSOON GAMES

February 2022 – September 2022

- Developed Gulp, a point and click simulator, using Unreal Engine 4.
- Responsible for all programming related tasks such as:
 - Creating the management systems that support day cycles, global and individual scores, dynamic request generation, etc.
 - Dealing with object physics and restricting their behaviours.
 - o Implementation of UI and sounds to support game features.

GAME PROGRAMMER, WITCH CAT GAMES

February 2021 - July 2021

- Developed Lyzzy, a 2D platformer, using Unreal Engine 4.
- Responsible for all Programming related tasks and implementation of animations, UI and sound.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN GAMES AND MULTIMEDIA – INSTITUTO POLITÉCNICO DE LEIRIA – PORTUGAL

- Focused on C# and C++ programming.
- Game development in Unity and, especially, Unreal Engine.

- Game Design and documentation writing.
- Marketing & Business.

OTHER ACCOMPLISHMENTS

 Accustomed to working with developing games in small teams and tight deadlines.